SAMEEHA RAHMAN

London, United Kingdom +447704467608 rahman.sameeha@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sameeha-rahman samsam-026.github.io github.com/samsam-026

FRONT END DEVELOPER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

An accomplished frontend-leaning full stack developer with 5+ years of experience in the logistics, energy and home services industries. A high-output engineer with a proven track record of implementing design-heavy UI, improving coding standards and architecture, enhancing user engagement and improving site SEO.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer | Housekeep Ltd. (Nov. 2022 – Present)

- Implemented design-heavy UI changes to customer facing app, improving engagement by 20%.
- Improved infrastructure of frontend repositories reducing code duplication and increasing tech velocity.
- Improved SEO score and page speed on marketing website by 50%.
- Increased unit testing coverage by 50% on owned app project.
- Developed features and maintained a self-contained React/Next.js project.
- Owned development and release process of native mobile apps.

Technology: TypeScript, Angular, Ionic, Next.js, React, Jasmine, Python, Django, AWS, Sentry, Jest, Cypress, Figma.

Senior Developer | Switchd Ltd. (Sept. 2020 - Nov. 2022)

- Defined and developed the company's coding and testing protocols.
- Mentored and onboarded new hires during their first few months to improve their velocity.
- Redesigned marketing site for brand update, increasing engagement by 20%.
- Implemented company finance processes using Xero APIs, saving 75% finance admin time.
- Reduce admin time on green home product installations by 50% for MakeMyHouseGreen.

Technology: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap, AWS, Sentry, React, Next.js.

EDUCATION

M. Sc. Computer Science | Queen Mary University of London (Sept. 2020 – Oct. 2022)

Awarded **MSc with Distinction** for a 2-year part-time Computer Science postgraduate degree. Studied Functional Programming, Interactive System Design, Mobile Services and Design for Human Interaction.

B. Eng. Software Engineering | University of Westminster (Sept. 2016 – July 2020)

Awarded **First Class Honours** for a 4-year Software Engineering undergraduate degree offered by the University of Westminster, UK.

ACTIVITIES

Developer | first-born (2019)

A React Native UI framework consisting of inbuilt components developed using Atomic design, with over 2000 downloads and 200 stars on GitHub. This highly customizable library allows UI components to render according to the underlying platform, following platform UX guidelines and reducing the work of front-end developers.

Technology: React Native, Jest, ESLint.